Kenny Alejandro Rios Avila

Graphic Designer and web developer

Calgary, AB T2V 0M5 kennyrgrafico@gmail.com +15878369256

With 12 years of experience in graphic design, web development, and UX/UI design, I specialize in creating user-friendly web interfaces to boost business growth. Proficient in web development and digital tools, I offer a unique blend of creativity and technical skills to enhance your online presence. Let's collaborate for a standout digital experience.

Portfolio: https://kennyrios.github.io/projects/

Password: riosavila29

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Web Developer

Avenue Living Asset Management-Calgary, AB October 2022 to Present

- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery to create user-centric web interfaces.
- Applied Responsive Web Design techniques, including React.js, grid systems, CSS media queries, and JavaScript DOM manipulation.
- Managed various CMS and Martech platforms, including WordPress, Drupal, SharePoint, Mailchimp, and HubSpot.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and delivered effective HTML email campaigns.
- Demonstrated graphic design proficiency using tools like Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign.
- Implemented Responsive Web Design principles for enhanced user experiences.
- Development of custom post types and advanced features using PHP and tools from Crocoblock among others.
- HubSpot CRM implementation.

Graphic Designer

Paul's Bakery-Vancouver, BC July 2022 to Present

- Digital Marketing
- Product design
- Web design

UX/UI Designer

MoltonRox Solutions Inc-Surrey, BC October 2021 to June 2022

• Development and design of websites using React and Shopify with great fast loading time speed and SEO optimization achieving a GTmetrix Grade of A.

- Increment the revenue by 25% by designing and implementing an Amazon e-commerce page and Shopify. Brand and packaging designs for the beauty industry with a great impact on sales in stores like Walmart,
- London Drugs and Amazon in the USA and Canada.
- increase of 50% of followers on Instagram by designing Posts and reels with valuable content helping brands like Urban Secrets to improve their engagement in the beauty market in the USA and Canada.

Web Development Teacher.

Devf-México

April 2021 to October 2021

• Incorporated engaging teaching methods and resources that set a strong foundation for learning, encouraging student participation and self-motivation to seek more information in one of the top 10 Latin America Bootcamps programs for learning programing • React • HTML 5 • CSS3 • JavaScript

WorldSkills web technologies expert

Workskills-Bogotá, Cundinamarca May 2018 to December 2020

WorldSkills web technologies expert for Colombia. Jury of WorldSkills international Kazan Rusia 2019

Graphic Design and Multimedia Teacher

Sena-Bogotá, Cundinamarca November 2014 to December 2020

- Web technologies and graphic design instructor recognized with the title of web technologies expert by WorldSkills International year 2019.
- Trainer in web technologies skill competition in WorldSkills Kazan-Russia in 2019. I taught people of all ages and backgrounds like elders, minor offenders, low-income teenagers, and adult professionals in different fields of technology like computer literacy, illustration, and programming.
- Instructor of:
- Graphic Designer and Front End
- Adobe Animate
- Web usability
- HTML & CSS Interface Design
- Javascript
- Google Analytics & SEO.

Front End Developer

Webhouse-Bogotá, Cundinamarca July 2013 to November 2014

• Leader in the web development team, implementing CMS technologies like WordPress, Joomla, and Front End Development using HTML 5, CSS, and JavaScript achieving improved companies revenue by 25%.

Graphic Designer

BBB EQUIPOS-Bogotá, Cundinamarca May 2012 to July 2013

• 1,00,000 dollars revenue from events where I design and develop an auction website, Event stands, magazines, and brochures in 2012.

Prepress Technician (Internship).

Imágenes y textos-Bogotá, Cundinamarca June 2007 to January 2008

Graphic design and digital pre press internship

Education

Post Degree Diploma in Computer And Information Systems

Douglas College - New Westminster, BC January 2021 to May 2022

AEC / DEP or Skilled Trade Certificate in Development and design

Universidad Piloto de Colombia 2013

Bachelor's in Graphic Design

Fundación Universidad Jorge Tadeo Lozano - Bogotá, CO January 2008 to May 2012

High School Degree in Architectural Design high school

Colegio Técnico Benjamín Herrera - Bogotá, CO January 2001 to December 2006

Skills

- Adobe Photoshop (8 years)
- CSS (8 years)
- Git (Less than 1 year)
- HTML5 (8 years)
- JavaScript (1 year)
- Web Development (2 years)
- WordPress (1 year)
- Node.js (Less than 1 year)
- Adobe XD (3 years)
- Adobe Illustrator (8 years)
- Adobe InDesign (8 years)
- Adobe Animate (8 years)
- Adobe Premiere (5 years)
- Adobe After Effects (1 year)
- User Interface (UI) (4 years)
- Web Design (5 years)
- Bootstrap (4 years)
- Java (1 year)
- C# (Less than 1 year)

- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Graphic Design (9 years)
- GitHub
- MySQL
- Computer Science
- Java (Less than 1 year)
- Android development (Less than 1 year)
- React (1 year)
- XML
- JSON
- Unity
- · Communication skills
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Microsoft Office
- jQuery (3 years)
- Sketch
- SQL
- User Experience (UX)
- Marketing (4 years)
- Advertising
- Public relations (8 years)
- Marketing, Advertising & Public Relations
- Figma (2 years)
- Marketing (2 years)
- Facebook Advertising (1 year)
- Marketing
- Advertising (5 years)
- Public relations (2 years)
- Marketing, Advertising & Public Relations (5 years)
- PHP
- Jira
- Front-End Development
- MongoDB
- · Express.js
- 2D animation
- Flutter
- Android development
- SQL

Languages

- Spanish ExpertEnglish Fluent

Links

https://kennyrios.github.io/projects/